Arizona Claude Edwards



Washington, DC 202 888 5614

arizonace@gmail.com



Skills					
Skill	YoE	Engagement	Rating	Description/Keywords	
Classic C++	10+		****	ATL, MFC, also: FCL, C++/CLI, OWL. etc.	
Modern C++	3		****	STL, AIX, Solaris, Linux	
C#/DotNet	8		****	Windows Forms, DLLs, Interop, Web ASP.NET	
Python	2*		****	PEP-008, multiprocessing, .NET and C++ Interop	
JavaScript	2*		****	Web, Bloomberg Terminal, Node, Typescript.	
Java/Kotlin	5		****	Enterprise Java, Android, JNI, Web-Applets, Tomcat	
Windows	10+		****	Since 3.0, Internals, SDK, GDI/+, COM/+	
Web	5+		****	ASP.Net, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Frameworks	
Unix	3		****	AIX, Solaris, Linux; Darwin (MacOS), Bloomberg	
Cloud	5		****	AWS, DynamoDB, SQS, S3, Elasticsearch, Serverless	
Databases	10+	∼~~	****	Design, DDL, Data Tier, SQL, NoSQL, Desktop	
TCP/IP	3	<u>~~~</u>	****	SSH, SSL/TLS; WS_FTP - fastest FTP client at the time	
IPTV	5		****	ASP.Net MRML to set-top-box, VHO integration.	

While I do not claim to maintain focused expertise in all the above simultaneously, I have a strong inventory of current and refreshable skills and solution finding experience. The table above is my attempt to estimate and depict for each skill my:

⋄ accumulated experience; ⋄ engagement over time; ⋄ overall self rating.

I look forward to the opportunity to demonstrate my skills, and contribute positively to your organization.

Aspects					
Multi-Sector	Experience in Financial, Healthcare, Education, Defense, Internet, TV, and other industries.				
Travel/Consulting	Traveling for trade shows, client meetings, collaboration, and recruiting.				
User Experience	UX/UI designing, building, testing including for limited input devices such as phones and TVs.				
Multimedia	Programming, encoding, decoding, and delivering image, video, and music formats.				
Algorithms	Efficiently identifying and applying the appropriate algorithms and data structures.				
Team Lead	Experience and recognition as team lead, principal developer, guide, and mentor.				
low level coding	Coding at the bit level, endianness, protocols, layouts, MIL-STD-1553, Arduino, etc.				

Education References

BSc in Computer Science with Math Minor Georgia State University

<u>linkedin.com/in/arizona-edwards#recommendations</u>

Download

Work Experience Summary							
Amazon	Software Development Engineer II	Dec 2016 to Feb 2023					
Developed cloud-based, large-scale financial micros	services in Java, Kotlin, and AWS.						
Bloomberg	Senior Software Engineer	Jun 2013 to Jun 2016					
Developed enterprise data delivery solutions concerning fixed income securities in C++, Python, SQL, etc.							
Georgia Tech Research Institute	Contract Programmer	Apr 2012 to May 2013					
Developed software to test aircraft missile defense systems using MILSTD1553 in C++, C# and Python.							
Alcatel-Lucent	Solution Line Manager	May 2009 to Mar 2012					
Implemented software solutions for IPTV television	and telephone service providers using C#	f, SQL, Java, etc.					
AT&T	Contract Programmer	Jan 2007 to Dec 2008					
Developed interactive IPTV software for the U-Vers	e platform in C#, JavaScript, and SQL.						
Agile Technologies LLC	Contract Programmer	Jan 2006 to Mar 2006					
Developed an Active-X control for Greyhound Packa	ageXpress in C++						
NextGen Healthcare Information Systems	Consultant	Jan 2005 to Aug 2006					
Implemented regulatory and migration solutions fo	r healthcare providers in C#, SQL, Excel, e	etc.					
taxslayer.com	Senior Developer	Sep 2003 to Nov 2004					
Developed online tax filing software in VB.Net, C# and SQL and using MSMQ.							
Ipswitch	Principal Software Developer	Mar 1999 to Sep 2003					
Developed versions of WS_FTP and other retail Int	ernet software in C++.						
Asymetrix	Contract Programmer	Jan 1997 to Feb 1999					
Implemented online eLearning solutions for enterp	rises in ToolBook OpenScript, C++, etc.						
Delta Airlines	Senior Contract Programmer	Jan 1996 to Nov 1996					
Developed airline reservations system software in 0	C++.						
The Federal Reserve Bank	Contract Programmer	May 1994 to Dec 1995					
Developed internal accounting and management so	oftware in C++ and SQL.						

Contract Programmer

Multimedia Technologist

Solution Generalist

Developed ETL and analysis software for credit card transaction data in VB, C, and C++.

Developed Computer Based Training and kiosk systems, maintained multimedia technology in the lab.

Nova Information Systems

The Hypermedia and Visualization Lab

Produced standardized tests for the state of Georgia.

The Georgia Assessment Project

Arizona Claude Edwards - Page 2

Sep 1993 to May 1994

Jul 1992 to Aug 1993

Jul 1989 to Aug 1992